Guide to the School of Hotel Administration Photographs and Ephemera 1920-2015
School of Hotel Administration Photographs and Ephemera
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
School of Hotel Administration Photographs and Ephemera, 1920-2015
28-10-4164
Cornell University. School of Hotel Administration.
5.6 cubic feet.
Photographs, publications, newspapers.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes photographs, publications and newspaper clippings concerning the Statler Hotel and School of Hotel Administration.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes photographs, publications and newspaper clippings concerning the Statler Hotel and School of Hotel Administration.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Faculty.
Subjects:
Hotel management schools -- New York (State) -- Ithaca.; Hospitality industry.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
See also the research material collected for the book Hospitality Leadership: Cornell Hotel School, #28-12-3774.
SERIES LIST
Series I. History
Boxes 1, 2 and 3
Series II. Photographs
Boxes 1, 4, 5
Series III. Slides
Boxes 4.5
Series IV. "Life is Service" History of the Hotel School written in 1995
Boxes 2
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. History
- Newspapers clippings, publications and programs, about the Hotel School, 1920-1949 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Newspapers clippings and publications about the Hotel School, 1950-1959 (Box 1, Folder 2-3)
- Newspapers clippings and publications about the Hotel School, 1958-1959 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Newspapers clippings and publications about the Hotel School, including 1989 issue of "The Statler Times", 1960-1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Newspapers Clippings and Publications about the Hotel School, including the first issue of the student newsletter "The Statler Times", 1986-1989 (Box 1, Folder 7-10)
- Newspapers Clippings and Publications pertaining to the Hotel School Campaign, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Postcards of Statler Hall (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Hotel School Scholarship Assistance, including Industry Cooperative Scholarship Program, 1968-1974 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Hotel Research and Development, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Educational Committee Report, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Hotel Progress Report, 1932 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Hotel Staff Organization and Expense Distribution, no date (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Hotel School Memo "Update", 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Faculty Publications List, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Working Paper Series - Abstracts, 1987-1990 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Correspondence from Alumni who donated items and 1961 Speech given by unidentified person, 1988 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Hotel School 50th Anniversary - Invitations, Programs, Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Drinking glass with "Statler" engraved on it, no date (Box 3)
- Series II. Photographs
- Statler Family - unidentified, no dates (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Alice Seidler Statler - Original Portrait by Bradford Bachrach, no date (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Buildings (Statler Hall and Hotel), Classes, People, Events, Associations, pertaining to the Hotel School, 1920s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 15-28)
- Meeting of Hotelmen, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- First Students in Hotel Administration, 1922 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- First Class in Hotel Administration to Graduate, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Troy Photographs of the Hotel School - Faculty and Students, two different photos, including one with Martha Van Rensselaer (2 copies), 1929 (Map-case DD-18)
- Eleventh Annual Dinner of the Buffalo Hotel Association in the Lafayette Hotel, 1921-05-14 (Map-case DD-18)
- Luncheon of the Visiting Hotelmen at the Hotel Pennsylvania in New York (2 copies), 1929 (Map-case DD-18)
- Luncheon (2 copies) of the Visiting Hotelmen at the Hotel Pennsylvania in New York, 1930 (Map-case DD-18)
- Luncheon that appears to have taken place at Cornell, circa 1930 (Map-case DD-18)
- Graduating Class with Students Identified, 1931 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Annual Dinner Cornell Society of Hotelmen at the Hotel Lincoln, 1935-11-12 (Map-case DD-18)
- Bellboy, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Student Body Assembled on the Steps of Bailey Hall, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Graduating Class, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Students with Professor John Courtney, 1941 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Vernon and Gordon Stouffer, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Cornell Society of Hotelmen - Waldorf Astoria, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Items from Scrapbook of Helen Tetter Kennedy, 1943-1947 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Headquarters for Pacific Coast Hotel Men's Club, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- National Hotel Exposition - Thirty First Annual Luncheon, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Professor Charles Sayles, John Larkin, Fred Mills, 1948 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Students, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Statler Inn Lounge and Main Dining Room, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Unidentified Group Photos, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Statler Inn Lounge, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Students working and Howard Meek, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Professor and Mrs. Elizabeth Toth; Commercial Gas Breakfast with Howard Meek, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Library, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- New York Hotel Reception with Dean Meek, Lee Schoenbrunn, John Borhman and Adrian Phillips, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Students including Howard Meek, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Groundbreaking for Statler Auditorium, including Deane Malott, Howard Meek and Alice Statler, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Unidentified Group Photos, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Hotel Management Workshop, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Cornell Hotel Society Leadership Photos, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Cornell Society of Hotelmen - Waldorf Astoria, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Annual Cornell Smoker - Hilton Statler Hotel, 1958-11-04 (Map-case DD-18)
- Banquet at Princess Kaiulani Hotel, J.B. Herndon, donated Recipe Collection, 1959 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Cornell Quarterly, 1960-1969 (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Second Generation Hotelies, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Summer Session and Various Other Group Photos, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Burton Sack and Dean Robert Beck - Scholarship Presentation, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Summer Session, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Events, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Professor John and Mrs. Peggy Sherry and Mary Wright, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Events, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Statler Inn Lobby, 1973-07 (Map-case DD-18)
- William Wallace Dietz Memorial Scholarship Awards Presentation, 1974-1975 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Events, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Signing of the IMHI/ESSEC Agreement, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Vance Christian - Villa Banfi Professor of Wine Education, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Career Interviews, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 38)
- Classrooms, Student Lounge, Faculty - Contact Sheets, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 39)
- Statler Hall Exteriors, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 40)
- Contact Sheets, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 41)
- Wine Class in Auditorium, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 42)
- Binenkorb Video and Computer Center, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 43)
- Classroom, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 44)
- Dean Jack Clark, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 45)
- Leadership Campaign Kickoff - Waldorf Astoria, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Leadership Campaign Kickoff -Washington, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 47)
- Leadership Campaign Lowe's Breakfast, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 48)
- Leadership Campaign Kickoff - Northeast, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 49)
- Leadership Campaign Kickoff - Upstate, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 50)
- Leadership Campaign Kickoff - Chicago, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 51)
- Leadership Campaign Kickoff - Orlando, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 52)
- Leadership Campaign Kickoff - Pittsburg, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 53)
- Leadership Campaign Final Meeting, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 54)
- Events, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 55)
- Topping Off Ceremony - Statler, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 56)
- Reunion- Peter and Nancy Meinig, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 57)
- James McLamore - Co-founder Burger King, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 58)
- Hotelie of the Year Award Banquet, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 59)
- Hall of Fame Dinner, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 60)
- Reconstruction of Parking Lot, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 61)
- Reconstruction of Parking Lot, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 62)
- Career Day, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 63)
- Statler Hotel Grand Opening, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Peter Plaza Dedication, Hercules sculpture by Seeley, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Society of Minority Hoteliers, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Wine Library with David Milligan and Professor Stephen Mutkoski, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Quarterly Staff, 1980-1989 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Contact Sheets, 1980-1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Career Days, 1980-1999 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Statler Hotel and School, Pre 1989 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Statler Hotel and School, 1980-1999 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Statler Hotel and School, 1980-1999 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Photographs of Robert Beck, Founding Director of IMHI, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Unidentified Photograph of Gentleman (Map-case DD-18)
- CDs of photos of various events, programs, people, buildings, etc., 2004-2015; CD-4017-4616 (Box 6-7)
- Series III. Slides
  - Hotel Automoation, 1976-1982 (Box 4)
  - Statler Renovation, Events, Faculty and Staff, Students, Classes, Buildings, Facilities, Exteriors, 1970-1989 (Box 4)
  - Hotel Graduates, 1996 (Box 4)
  - Beck Center, 2003-2004 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Series IV. "Life is Service" History of the Hotel School written in 1995
  - Correspondence, Drafts of the book "Life of Service", 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 11-14)
  - Correspondence from Alumni, including memorabilia collected for the writing of the book, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence from E.M. Statler, 1921-1924 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mary Wright's comments about "Life is Service", 1995 (Box 2, Folder 17)